### KATHLEEN CHARTIER

**DATA ANALYST** 

Nashua, NH ◆ Kathleenf.chartier@gmail.com ◆ 603-498-6116 ◆ LinkedIn ◆ Data Portfolio ◆ Tableau

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst who is curious to find out what insights data will provide and anxious to share results to drive decisions. Successful experience as engineer and mathematics educator has created solid foundation of professional skills such as Problem-solving, Critical Thinking, Effective Collaboration, Customer Focused, Organization, Time management, Project Management, Presentation, Communication, Self-motivation, Adaptability, Attention to Detail, Quick Learner

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Tableau, SQL, Microsoft Excel, Python, Google Suite, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Microsoft Office Suite, IBM Cognos, Jupyter Notebooks

### **PROJECTS**

<u>Need Food Now?</u> Skills: Excel, Pivot Tables, Pivot Charts, Scatterplot, Histogram, Radial Chart I used data from a food delivery app to determine which demographics spend the most and whether marketing campaigns increased customer spending.

<u>Is student success affected by socioeconomic factors</u>? **Skills: SQL, Python, Matplotlib** I used data from the city of Chicago and analyzed it to determine if there is a correlation between student success and socioeconomic status.

<u>Chartier Family Spotify Wrapped!</u> Skills: Tableau, Python and Spotipy, JSON files, Excel I used Spotify data from all the family members and created a dashboard to analyze top songs, artists, genres and more!

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Consultant - Business Data Analyst**

September – October 2023, Eagle Biosciences, Amherst, NH

Interpreted **client needs** to create two <u>dashboards</u> using Excel that are used to gauge business and market growth in target areas. Dashboards created with two different data sets provided by client and will update as new data is added. Process included **data cleaning**, **pivot tables**, **pivot charts**, **slicers for filtering** items across multiple pivot tables and **dashboard slicers** for filtering by month and year.

## **Mathematics Educator**

August 2019 – June 2022, Salem School District, Salem, NH, Salem High School Grades 9-11, Geometry, Algebra 2

August 2011 – June 2019, Merrimack School District, Merrimack, NH, Merrimack Middle School Grade 8, Pre-Algebra, Algebra 1

September 2010 – June 2011, Nashua School District, Nashua, NH, Pennichuck Middle School Grade 8, Pre-Algebra, Algebra 1

#### **Educator Responsibilities and Skills**

- Management of instructional timeline for multiple curriculums (course and academic level)
- Planning and creation of instructional materials and presentations to meet learning goals
- Collect and analyze student assessments data
- Collaboration with colleagues on curriculum and common assessments
- Manage student information using various technology tools (PowerSchool, Infinite Campus)
  Proficient use of Microsoft Office Suite and Google Suite

# **Mechanical Engineer**

January 2000 – February 2009, Brooks Automation, Inc., Chelmsford, MA

Designed, created documentation and provided manufacturing support for automation systems and components for the semiconductor industry using solid modeling design software. Components ranged in size and complexity from small electrical and communication packages to large clean room equipment enclosures.

# **Mechanical Design Engineer**

October 1998 – January 2000, Northern Research and Engineering Corporation, Portsmouth, NH Designed, created documentation and provided manufacturing support for systems and components for cogeneration gas microturbine using solid modeling design software.

### **Accessories Engineer, Project Engineer**

February 1995 – October 1998, International Equipment Company, Needham, MA Managed centrifuge accessories product line. Developed process and procedure for handling custom accessory requests from customers. Designed, created documentation and provided manufacturing support for new centrifuges using solid modeling design software and internal business systems.

# Aftermarket Engineer, Navy Product Engineer

June 1989 – February 1995, General Electric Company, Fitchburg, MA

Calculated upgrade potential for commercial steam turbines using propriety software. Designed of support structures and thermodynamic turbine steam path for Naval propulsion turbines and turbine generators.

# **Engineering Responsibilities and Skills**

- Problem solving during design process to meet design requirements
- Collaboration and communication with internal and external customers during design process
- Managing project timelines
- **Presentation** of designs and design evolution.
- Successful use of various business systems and technology tools for design, testing, documentation, engineering changes and parts procurement

#### **EDUCATION**

Data Analyst Professional Certificate, Coursera - January 2023

# Teacher Education Conversion Program, Mathematics, NHTI, Concord, NH

May 2019, Upper Level Certification

May 2010, Middle School Certification

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Cum Laude, University of New Hampshire, Nashua, NH

May 1994

**Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Cum Laude**, Northeastern University, Boston, MA June 1989